Phone: (937) 775-5217

Email: sadeghi.2@wright.edu, reza@knoesis.org Homepage: http://knoesis.org/Reza

Location: 377 Joshi Research Center, Wright State University, 3640 Colonel Glenn Highway, OH, USA 45435

Personal Statement

Reza Sadeghi has attended the department of computer science and engineering at Wright State University as a PhD student in computer science. Right now, he is a graduate research assistant at Data Science for Healthcare lab in the Ohio Center of Excellence in Knowledge-enabled Computing (kno.e.sis). He has achieved to publish several research papers in precious journals and conferences with high impact factors. Also, he is reviewer and program committee member of top conferences and journals such as WWW conference, JMIR, and IEEE Transactions on Fuzzy Systems.

Currently, he is working on three projects of patient monitoring system, structure learning, and dementia management. Through his research, he deals with different concepts especially, probabilistic graphical model, signal processing, and soft computing techniques. His focus is on creating a smart clinical decision support system based on state-of-the-art machine learning methods.

Education

Ph. D., Computer Science (GPA:4.0)

May 2017 - Present

Wright State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Dayton, Ohio, USA

M.S., Computer Engineering- Software (GPA:4.0)

Sep 2013 - May 2015

International Imam Reza University, Department of Computer and Information Technology, Mashhad, Iran Thesis: Strengthening Support Vector Classifiers against Outliers by using Fuzzy Rough Set and Evolutionary Methods

B.S., Computer Engineering- Software

Sep 2008 - Sep 2012

Isfahan University of Technology, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Isfahan, Iran Project: Designing & implementation of online library management website in IUT High School

Research Interests

Information retrieval from online medical literatures and social media

Design and implementation of Expert Systems with the aim of outlier detection

Modeling complex systems using probabilistic graphical models, deep learning, and Fuzzy Logic

Clinical decision support systems based on the state-of-the-art machine learning and signal processing methods

Research Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

May 2017 – Present

Kno.e.sis Research Center, Wright State University, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Creating knowledge graph based on medical literatures

Tracking social media users under the effects of alcohol

Applying probabilistic graphical model structure learning in learning progress

Detecting changes in behavior and activity patterns of dementia caregivers by analyzing their vital signals Using signal processing and soft computing to predict the early hospital mortality by scrutinizing the vital signs

Graduate Research Assistant

Nov 2013 – Mar 2017

International Imam Reza University, Department of Computer and Information Technology, Mashhad, Iran Customer Prediction in Furniture store based on Artificial Neural Network

Feature Reduction and Selection based on Fuzzy Rough Set

Handwriting detection based on Hidden Markov Model

Heart problem diagnosis via Fourier transform signal processing

Nurse scheduling based on Stochastic Programming

Teaching Experience

Teaching Graduate Assistant

Sep 2014 – May 2015

International Imam Reza University, Department of Computer and Information Technology, Mashhad, Iran Advanced mathematics in computer engineering: The applications of fuzzy logic by MATLAB Fuzzy toolbox Multimedia systems: Creating dynamic website using HTML 5, CSS, and Java Script Advanced Computer programming & Computer programming: Basic concepts of C and C++

Technical Strengths

Database: PostgreSQL, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server

Programming language: R, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, C#, C, C++, JavaScript, Python, ASP.NET

Packages: bnlearn, RPostgreSQL, caret, Scikit-learn, igraph, network, RCrawler, Keras, TenseorFlow, Isa,

OpenNLP, Rmatlab

Journal Publications

- R. Sadeghi, T. Banerjee, W. Romine (2018), "Early Hospital Mortality Prediction using Vital Signals", Smart Health (special proceeding of IEEE&ACM CHASE 2018), In Press.
- J. Hamidzadeh, M. Zabihimayvan, **R. Sadeghi** (2018), "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets", Soft Computing, 22(7), 147-158, April 2018. (Impact factor: 2.472)
- R. Sadeghi, J. Hamidzadeh (2018), "Automatic support vector data description", Soft Computing, 22(1), 147-158, January 2018. (Impact factor: 2.472)
- M. Zabihimayvan, **R. Sadeghi**, H. NathanRude, D. Doran (2017), "A soft computing approach for benign and malicious web robot detection", Expert Systems with Applications, 87, 129-140, November 2017. (Impact factor: 3.928)
- J. Hamidzadeh, **R. Sadeghi**, Neda Namaei (2017), "Weighted support vector data description based on chaotic bat algorithm", Applied Soft Computing, 60, 540-551, November 2017. (Impact factor: 3.541)
- Gholinezhad Devin, K. Abedzadeh Ghuchani, **R. Sadeghi**, H. Koosha (2015), "Dynamic Facility Location with Stochastic Demand", Shiraz Journal of System Management, 3:3, 77-90, Fall 2015.
- Gholinezhad Devin, K. Abedzadeh Ghuchani, **R. Sadeghi** (2013), "Stochastic Facilities location Model by Using Stochastic Programming", Shiraz Journal of System Management, 1:4, 59-71, October 2013

Conference Publications

- **R. Sadeghi**, J. Hamidzadeh (2015), "SVDD based on Rough fuzzy set", 20th National Conference of Iranian computer committee (CSICC2015), March 3, 2015 (In Persian).
- **R. Sadeghi**, A. Shaeen, H. Abbasi, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Inducing intuitionistic fuzzy decision tree based on maximum ambiguity in big data", Second International Conference on Intelligent Information Networks and Complex Systems (IINCS2014), November 26, 2014 (In Persian).
- J. Arefi, J. Hamidzadeh, A. Gholinezhad Devin, **R. Sadeghi**, S. Fayaz (2014), "Balancing time, cost, quality and network resources by considering time value of money and extended Fuzzy Logic", Fourteenth Iranian Conference on Fuzzy Systems (ICFS2014), August 19, 2014 (In Persian).
- R. Sadeghi, A. Shaeen, M. Vafaijahan (2014), "Improving fast Distance Vector convergence Protocol using enhanced Hidden Markov Model", First National Conference on Computer Engineering and Information Technology Management (CEITM2014), May 29, 2014 (In Persian).
- J. Hamidzadeh, A. Shaeen, **R. Sadeghi** (2014), "Using Fuzzy Logic to Solving Worm Hole Attack", First National Conference on Computer Engineering and Information Technology Management (CEITM2014), May 29, 2014 (In Persian).

- Gholinezhad Devin, **R. Sadeghi**, M. Hasan Nejat, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Project scheduling with resource constraints using fuzzy model extension", Seventh International conference of Iranian Operations Research Society (OR2014), May 14, 2014 (In Persian).
- Gholinezhad Devin, K. Abedzadeh Ghuchani, **R. Sadeghi**, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Dynamic Stochastic facility location using random scheduling", Seventh International conference of Iranian Operations Research Society (OR2014), May 14, 2014 (In Persian).
- V. Fazelinia, A. Ebrahimi Moghaddam, **R. Sadeghi**, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Robot routing with hybrid fuzzy logic and HMM", First National Conference on ECSS (Moj 2014), May 10, 2014 (In Persian).

Patent

M. Zabihimayvan, **R. Sadeghi**, D. Doran (2018), "Soft Computing Methods for Feature Selection for Web Agent Detection", June 2018, U.S. Provisional Patent, Pending.

Leadership and Service Activities

- The program committee of WWW, ICACR, Biomedical Research, IntelliSys, Computing conference (2018)
- The referee of IEEE Transactions on Fuzzy Systems (Feb 2018- Present), Journal of Medical Internet Research (Aug 2018- Present), International Journal of Science and Business (Jun 2018- Present), and IEEE Big Data 2018
- Academic outreach coordinator of Biomedical Research and Technology Association (Feb 2018- Present)
- SIGIR conference student volunteer, Ann Arbor, MI (2018)

Honors and Awards

- Received NSF travel award for IEEE/ACM CHASE2018, Washington, D.C., 2018
- Best paper award for publishing "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets", 2017
- Best paper award for publishing "Automatic support vector data description", 2016.
- Top researcher at Imam Reza International University, 2016

Certifications

Seminar on Artificial Intelligence & Virtual Reality with Bayesian Networks & BayesiaLab Bayesia, License CREDLY-14502538	Feb 2018- Present
Probabilistic Graphical Models 1: Representation (with Honors) Stanford University on Coursera, License 93VRVV253F72	Sep 2017- Present
Course Completion in Biomedical Research Investigators Collaborative Institutional Training (CITI), Record ID 23266575	Jun 2017-Jun 2020
Course Completion in Data or Specimens Only Research Collaborative Institutional Training (CITI), Record ID 23266577	Jun 2017-Jun 2020
Course Completion in Responsible Conduct of Research for Biomedical Collaborative Institutional Training (CITI), Record ID 23266576	Jun 2017-Jun 2020
Internet searching methodologies & Referencing techniques by Zotero Research Management at Imam Reza International University, License 16793	Dec 2014 - Present

References

1. Dr. Saeedeh Shekarpour

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science University of Dayton, College Park, Dayton, OH 45469-2160 sshekarpour1@udayton.edu 2. Dr. Mehdi Allahyari
Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science
Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA 30460
mallahyari@georgiasouthern.edu

3. Dr. Derek Doran Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering Wright State University, 3640 Colonel Glenn Hwy, Dayton, OH 45435 derek.doran@wright.edu

Others

Iran citizen